Finding Aid for Marion L. Burton Papers 1895-1925
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- President's Office Correspondence Files, 1920-1925; 18.5 linear feet
  - 1921-1922
    - Minnesota, University of (Box 7)
      (7-15)
    - Moa-My (Box 7)
      (7-16)
    - Murfin, James Orin (Box 7)
      (7-17)
    - Na-Ne (Box 7)
      (7-18)
    - Near East Relief (Box 7)
      (7-19)
    - Ni-Nz (Box 7)
      (7-20)
    - Oa-Oz (Box 7)
      (7-21)
    - Osborn, Chase Salmon (Box 7)
      (7-22)
    - Pa-Pe (Box 7)
      (7-23)
    - Pardon, E. C. (Box 7)
      (7-24)
    - Parnell, C. G. (Box 7)
      (7-25)
    - Parker, John C. (Box 7)
      (7-26)
    - Pf-Pi (Box 7)
      (7-27)
    - Pharmacy, College of (Box 7)
      (7-28)
    - Pl-Po (Box 7)
      (7-29)
    - Pomeroy, Mrs. Edward D. (Box 7)
      (7-30)
    - Pr-Q (Box 7)
      (7-31)
    - Quarterly, University of Michigan (Box 8)
      (8-1)
    - Ra-Ri (Box 8)
      (8-2)
    - Radio Letters (Box 8)
      (8-3)
    - Regents (Box 8)
      (8-4)
    - Riggs, H. E. (Box 8)
      (8-5)
    - Ro-Rz (Box 8)
      (8-6)
    - Sa-Sch (Box 8)
      (8-7)
    - Sci-Se (Box 8)
      (8-8)
    - Sawyer, W. H. (Box 8)
      (8-9)
    - Sh-Sl (Box 8)
      (8-10)
    - Shaw, Wilfred Byron (Box 8)
      (8-11)
    - Shepard, John L. (Box 8)
      (8-12)
    - Sink Charles Albert (Box 8)
      (8-13)
    - Sm-So (Box 8)
      (8-14)
    - Smith, Shirley Wheeler (Box 8)
      (8-15)
    - Sp-Sq (Box 8)
      (8-16)
    - Springer, D. W. (Box 8)
      (8-17)
    - St (Box 8)
      (8-18)
    - Su-Sz (Box 8)
      (8-19)
    - Sundwall, John W. (Box 8)
      (8-20)
    - Ta-Th (Box 8)
      (8-21)
    - Tk-Tz (Box 8)
      (8-22)
    - Treasurer (Box 8)
      (8-23)
    - U (Box 8)
      (8-24)
    - United States (Box 8)
      (8-25)
    - University Hospital (Box 8)
      (8-26)
    - Va (Box 8)
      (8-27)
    - Ve-Vz (Box 8)
      (8-28)
    - Vocational Education (Box 8)
      (8-29)
    - Waa-Waz (Box 8)
      (8-30)
    - U.S. War Department (Box 8)
      (8-31)
    - Ward, M. L. (Box 8)
      (8-32)
    - Wea-Wh (Box 9)
      (9-1)
    - White, A. E. (Box 9)
      (9-2)
    - White, A. H. (Box 9)
      (9-3)
    - Whitney, A. S. (Box 9)
      (9-4)
    - Wia-Woz (Box 9)
      (9-5)
    - Wiley, Merlin (Box 9)
      (9-6)
    - Wr-Z (Box 9)
      (9-7)
    - Yost, Fielding Harris (Box 9)
      (9-8)
  - 1922-1923
    - Aa-An (Box 9)
      (9-9)
    - American Council on Education (Box 9)
      (9-10)
    - Ao-Az (Box 9)
      (9-11)
    - Arthur, Robert (Box 9)
      (9-12)
    - Associated Press (Box 9)
      (9-13)
    - Baa-Bal (Box 9)
      (9-14)
    - Bam-Baz (Box 9)
      (9-15)
    - Burton, R. M. (Box 9)
      (9-16)
    - Bates, Henry Moore (Box 9)
      (9-17)
    - Bea-Bk (Box 9)
      (9-18)
    - Beal, Junius Emery (Box 9)
      (9-19)
    - Bishop, William Warner (Box 9)
      (9-20)
    - Bl-Bq (Box 9)
      (9-21)
    - Bra-Brt (Box 9)
      (9-22)
    - Bru-Bz (Box 9)
      (9-23)
    - Bureau of Education (Box 9)
      (9-24)
    - Bursley, Joseph A. (Box 9)
      (9-25)
    - Burton, Marion LeRoy (Box 9)
      (9-26)
    - Caa-Cd (Box 9)
      (9-27)
    - Cabot, Hugh (Box 9)
      (9-28)
    - Carnegie Foundation (Box 9)
      (9-29)
    - Ce-Ch (Box 9)
      (9-30)
    - Ci-Cok (Box 10)
      (10-1)
    - Clements, William (Box 10)
      (10-2)
    - Col-Con (Box 10)
      (10-3)
    - Committee of Five-Building Program (Box 10)
      (10-4)
    - Coo-Coz (Box 10)
      (10-5)
    - Cooley, Mortimer (Box 10)
      (10-6)
    - Congregational Church (Box 10)
      (10-7)
    - Cp-Cz (Box 10)
      (10-8)
    - Da-Dd (Box 10)
      (10-9)
    - De-Dh (Box 10)
      (10-10)
    - Di-Dn (Box 10)
      (10-11)
    - Doa-Doz (Box 10)
      (10-12)
    - Dr-Dz (Box 10)
      (10-13)
    - Ea-Eh (Box 10)
      (10-14)
    - Effinger, John R. (Box 10)
      (10-15)
    - Ei-Ez (Box 10)
      (10-16)
    - Fa-Fn (Box 10)
      (10-17)
    - Frost, Robert (Box 10)
      (10-18)
    - Fo-Fz (Box 10)
      (10-19)
    - Ga-Gh (Box 10)
      (10-20)
    - Gi-Gq (Box 10)
      (10-21)
    - Gore, Victor M. (Box 10)
      (10-22)
    - Gra-Gz (Box 10)
      (10-23)
    - Groesbeck, Alexander J. (Box 10)
      (10-24)
    - Haa-Hd (Box 10)
      (10-25)
    - Hall, Arthur G. (Box 10)
      (10-26)
    - Hamilton, Jean (Box 10)
      (10-27)
    - Hanchett, Benjamin (Box 10)
      (10-28)
    - Hea-Hn (Box 10)
      (10-29)
    - Henderson, W. D. (Box 10)
      (10-30)
    - Hoa-Hok (Box 10)
      (10-31)
    - Hol-Hoz (Box 10)
      (10-32)
    - Hua-Hz (Box 11)
      (11-1)
    - Hubbard, Lucius (Box 11)
      (11-2)
    - Ia-Iz (Box 11)
      (11-3)
    - International Committee of YMCA (Box 11)
      (11-4)
    - Institute of International Education (Box 11)
      (11-5)
    - Ja-Jn (Box 11)
      (11-6)
    - Jo-Jz (Box 11)
      (11-7)
    - Johnson, T. E. (Box 11)
      (11-8)
    - Ka-Kh (Box 11)
      (11-9)
    - Kahn, Albert (Box 11)
      (11-10)
    - Kelsey, Francis Willey (Box 11)
      (11-11)
    - Ki (Box 11)
      (11-12)
    - Kj-Kz (Box 11)
      (11-13)
    - Kraus, E. H. (Box 11)
      (11-14)
    - Laa-Lh (Box 11)
      (11-15)
    - Statistics, figures, taxes, etc. (Box 11)
      (11-16)
    - Legislative publications of other universities (Box 11)
      (11-17)
    - Leland, Frank (Box 11)
      (11-18)
    - Li-Lt (Box 11)
      (11-19)
    - Lu-Lz (Box 11)
      (11-20)
    - Lloyd, Alfred (Box 11)
      (11-21)
    - Maa-Maz (Box 11)
      (11-22)
    - Manwaring, E. B. (Box 11)
      (11-23)
    - McA-McZ (Box 11)
      (11-24)
    - Mea-Mn (Box 11)
      (11-25)
    - Michigan Union (Box 11)
      (11-26)
    - Moa-Mz (Box 11)
      (11-27)
    - Mooney, C. H. (Box 11)
      (11-28)
    - Murfin, James Orin (Box 11)
      (11-29)
    - Na-Nh (Box 11)
      (11-30)
    - Ni-Nz (Box 11)
      (11-31)
    - Oa-Oz (Box 11)
      (11-32)
    - Osborn, Chase Salmon (Box 11)
      (11-33)
    - Pa-Pd (Box 12)
      (12-1)
    - Parnell, C. G. (Box 12)
      (12-2)
    - Pe (Box 12)
      (12-3)
    - Pf-Pq (Box 12)
      (12-4)
    - Pardon, E. C. (Box 12)
      (12-5)
    - Perry, Stuart H. (Box 12)
      (12-6)
    - Pr-Q (Box 12)
      (12-7)
    - Ra-Rg (Box 12)
      (12-8)
    - Regents (Box 12)
      (12-9)
    - Rh-Rt (Box 12)
      (12-10)
    - Riggs, H. E. (Box 12)
      (12-11)
    - Ru-Rz (Box 12)
      (12-12)
    - Sa-Sch (Box 12)
      (12-13)
    - Sawyer, Walter (Box 12)
      (12-14)
    - Sci-Sh (Box 12)
      (12-15)
    - Shaw, Wilfred Byron (Box 12)
      (12-16)
    - Shepard, J. F. (Box 12)
      (12-17)
    - Sink, Charles Albert (Box 12)
      (12-18)
    - Si-Ss (Box 12)
      (12-19)
    - Smith, Shirley Wheeler (Box 12)
      (12-20)
    - St (Box 12)
      (12-21)
    - Student Friendship Fund (Box 12)
      (12-22)
    - Su-Sz (Box 12)
      (12-23)
    - Sundwall, John (Box 12)
      (12-24)
    - Ta-Tg (Box 12)
      (12-25)
    - Th-Tq (Box 12)
      (12-26)
    - Tu-Tz (Box 12)
      (12-27)
    - Treasurer (Box 12)
      (12-28)
    - U (Box 12)
      (12-29)
    - United States (Box 12)
      (12-30)
    - Va-Vz (Box 12)
      (12-31)
    - Wa-Wd (Box 12)
      (12-32)
    - War Department (Box 12)
      (12-33)
    - Ward, M. L. (Box 12)
      (12-34)
    - Warnshuis, F. C. (Box 12)
      (12-35)
    - Wea-Wg (Box 12)
      (12-36)
    - Wh (Box 12)
      (12-37)
    - White, A. E. (Box 12)
      (12-38)
    - Whitney, A. S. (Box 12)
      (12-39)
    - Wia-Wn (Box 13)
      (13-1)
    - Woa-Wz (Box 13)
      (13-2)
    - X,Y,Z (Box 13)
      (13-3)
    - York, Edward (of York and Sawyer Architects) (Box 13)
      (13-4)
    - Yost, Fielding Harris (Box 13)
      (13-5)
  - 1923-1924
    - Aa-Ai (Box 13)
      (13-6)
    - Aj-An (Box 13)
      (13-7)
    - American Council on Education (Box 13)
      (13-8)
    - American University Union in Europe (Box 13)
      (13-9)
    - Annual Report (Box 13)
      (13-10)
    - Ao-Az (Box 13)
      (13-11)
    - Baa-Baz (Box 13)
      (13-12)
    - Be-Bi (Box 13)
      (13-13)
    - Bates, Henry Moore (Box 13)
      (13-14)
    - Beal, Junius Emery (Box 13)
      (13-15)
    - Bishop, William Warner (Box 13)
      (13-16)
    - Bl-Bre (Box 13)
      (13-17)
    - Bro-Brz (Box 13)
      (13-18)
    - Bridges, Robert (Box 13)
      (13-19)
    - Bu-Bz (Box 13)
      (13-20)
    - Bursley, Joseph A. (Box 13)
      (13-21)
    - Burton, Marion LeRoy (Box 13)
      (13-22)
    - Burton, Marion LeRoy (Box 13)
      (13-23)
    - Caa-Cd (Box 13)
      (13-24)
    - Cabot, Hugh (Box 13)
      (13-25)
    - Carnegie Foundation (Box 13)
      (13-26)
    - Carpenter, William T. (Box 13)
      (13-27)
    - Ce-Ch (Box 13)
      (13-28)
    - Christensen, J. C. (Box 13)
      (13-29)
    - Ci-Con (Box 14)
      (14-1)
    - Clements, William (Box 14)
      (14-2)
    - Clements Library (Box 14)
      (14-3)
    - Coffman, H. C.-Student Christian Association (Box 14)
      (14-4)
    - Committee of Five-Building Program (Box 14)
      (14-5)
    - Congregational Church (Box 14)
      (14-6)
    - Coo-Cz (Box 14)
      (14-7)
    - Cook, W. W. (Box 14)
      (14-8)
    - Cooley, Mortimer (Box 14)
      (14-9)
    - Couzens, James (Box 14)
      (14-10)
    - Creative Art Fellowship (Box 14)
      (14-11)
    - Da-Dd (Box 14)
      (14-12)
    - Day, E. E. (Box 14)
      (14-13)
    - De-Dh (Box 14)
      (14-14)
    - Di-Dz (Box 14)
      (14-15)
    - Contribution Fund for Dutch Literature and history (Box 14)
      (14-16)
    - Ea-Eh (Box 14)
      (14-17)
    - Ei-Ez (Box 14)
      (14-18)
    - Effinger, John (Box 14)
      (14-19)
    - English Speaking Union (Box 14)
      (14-20)
    - Fa-Fk (Box 14)
      (14-21)
    - Fl-Fz (Box 14)
      (14-22)
    - Ga-Gl (Box 14)
      (14-23)
    - Goa-Gz (Box 14)
      (14-24)
    - Gore, Victor M. (Box 14)
      (14-25)
    - Greve, Robert G. (Box 14)
      (14-26)
    - Groesbeck, Alexander J. (Box 14)
      (14-27)
    - Haa-Haq (Box 14)
      (14-28)
    - Hall, Arthur (Box 14)
      (14-29)
    - Hamilton, Jean (Box 14)
      (14-30)
    - Hanchett, Benjamin S. (Box 14)
      (14-31)
    - Har-Hd (Box 14)
      (14-32)
    - Hea-Hn (Box 14)
      (14-33)
    - Hoa-Ht (Box 14)
      (14-34)
    - Hua-Hz (Box 15)
      (15-1)
    - Hubbard, Lucius L. (Box 15)
      (15-2)
    - I (Box 15)
      (15-3)
    - International Committee of UMCA (Box 15)
      (15-4)
    - Institute of International Education (Box 15)
      (15-5)
    - Ja-Jz (Box 15)
      (15-6)
    - Ka-Kem (Box 15)
      (15-7)
    - Kahn, Albert (Box 15)
      (15-8)
    - Kelsey, Francis Willey (Box 15)
      (15-9)
    - Ken-Kz (Box 15)
      (15-10)
    - Kraus, E. H. (Box 15)
      (15-11)
    - Laa-Laz (Box 15)
      (15-12)
    - Le-Lk (Box 15)
      (15-13)
    - Ll-Lz (Box 15)
      (15-14)
    - Lloyd, Alfred (Box 15)
      (15-15)
    - Maa-Mb (Box 15)
      (15-16)
    - McA-Md (Box 15)
      (15-17)
    - Mea-Mh (Box 15)
      (15-18)
    - Mi-Mn (Box 15)
      (15-19)
    - Michigan League (Box 15)
      (15-20)
    - Moa-Mz (Box 15)
      (15-21)
    - Mulford, Walter (Box 15)
      (15-22)
    - Murfin, James Orin (Box 15)
      (15-23)
    - Na-Nh (Box 15)
      (15-24)
    - Near East Relief (Box 15)
      (15-25)
    - Nelson, J. R.-Art Theatre (Box 15)
      (15-26)
    - Ni-Nz (Box 15)
      (15-27)
    - Oa-On (Box 15)
      (15-28)
    - Or-Oz (Box 15)
      (15-29)
    - Pa-Pd (Box 15)
      (15-30)
    - Pardon, E. C. (Box 15)
      (15-31)
    - Parnell, C. G. (Box 15)
      (15-32)
    - Pe (Box 15)
      (15-33)
    - Pf-Q (Box 16)
      (16-1)
    - Pitkin, William, Jr. (Box 16)
      (16-2)
    - Ra-Rn (Box 16)
      (16-3)
    - Regents (Box 16)
      (16-4)
    - Riggs, E. H. (Box 16)
      (16-5)
    - Ro-Rz (Box 16)
      (16-6)
    - ROTC (Box 16)
      (16-7)
    - Rotary Club (Box 16)
      (16-8)
    - Sa-Sg (Box 16)
      (16-9)
    - Sawyer, Walter (Box 16)
      (16-10)
    - Sh (Box 16)
      (16-11)
    - Shepard, J. F. (Box 16)
      (16-12)
    - Si-So (Box 16)
      (16-13)
    - Smith, Shirley Wheeler (Box 16)
      (16-14)
    - Sp-St (Box 16)
      (16-15)
    - Strauss, F. W. (Box 16)
      (16-16)
    - Stone, Ralph (Box 16)
      (16-17)
    - Stone, Ralph (Box 16)
      (16-18)
    - Su-Sz (Box 16)
      (16-19)
    - Ta-Th (Box 16)
      (16-20)
    - Ti-Tz (Box 16)
      (16-21)
    - Todd, A. M. (Box 16)
      (16-22)
    - Treasurer's Report (Box 16)
      (16-23)
    - U (Box 16)
      (16-24)
    - United States (Box 16)
      (16-25)
    - University Hospital-Directorship (Box 16)
      (16-26)
    - University Hospital-Directorship (Box 16)
      (16-27)
    - Va-Vz (Box 17)
      (17-1)
    - Wa-Wd (Box 17)
      (17-2)
    - War Department (Box 17)
      (17-3)
    - Ward, M. L. (Box 17)
      (17-4)
    - Wea-Wh (Box 17)
      (17-5)
    - White, A.E. (Box 17)
      (17-6)
    - Whitney, A.S. (Box 17)
      (17-7)
    - Wia-Wil (Box 17)
      (17-8)
    - Wickersham Speech (Papers concerning) (Box 17)
      (17-9)
    - Wim-Wz (Box 17)
      (17-10)
    - X,Y,Z (Box 17)
      (17-11)
    - York and Sawyer (Box 17)
      (17-12)
    - Yost, Fielding Harris (Box 17)
      (17-13)
  - 1924-1925
    - Aa-Az (Box 17)
      (17-14)
    - American Council on Education (Box 17)
      (17-15)
    - Baa-Bh (Box 17)
      (17-16)
    - Baker, Oscar W. (Box 17)
      (17-17)
    - Bates, Henry Moore (Box 17)
      (17-18)
    - Beal, Junius Emery (Box 17)
      (17-19)
    - Bi-Bq (Box 17)
      (17-20)
    - Bishop, William Warner (Box 17)
      (17-21)
    - Bra-Bz (Box 17)
      (17-22)
    - Bureau of Education (Box 17)
      (17-23)
    - Bursley, Joseph A. (Box 17)
      (17-24)
    - Burton, Marion LeRoy (Box 17)
      (17-25)
    - Caa-Ch (Box 17)
      (17-26)
    - Cabot, Hugh (Box 17)
      (17-27)
    - Carnegie Foundation (Box 17)
      (17-28)
    - Carpenter, William T. (Box 17)
      (17-29)
    - Christensen, J.C. (Box 17)
      (17-30)
    - Ci-Con (Box 17)
      (17-31)
    - Clements, William (Box 17)
      (17-32)
    - Clements Library (Box 17)
      (17-33)
    - Coffman, H.C.-Student Christian Association (Box 17)
      (17-34)
    - Committee of Five-Building Program (Box 17)
      (17-35)
    - Cook, W.W. (Box 18)
      (18-1)
    - Coo-Cz (Box 18)
      (18-2)
    - Cooley, Mortimer (Box 18)
      (18-3)
    - Congregational Foundation for Education (Box 18)
      (18-4)
    - Creative Arts (Box 18)
      (18-5)
    - Da-Dh (Box 18)
      (18-6)
    - Day, E.E. (Box 18)
      (18-7)
    - Di-Dz (Box 18)
      (18-8)
    - Ea-Eh (Box 18)
      (18-9)
    - Effinger, John R. (Box 18)
      (18-10)
    - Ei-Ez (Box 18)
      (18-11)
    - Fa-Fq (Box 18)
      (18-12)
    - Fr-Fz (Box 18)
      (18-13)
    - Ga-Gl (Box 18)
      (18-14)
    - Goa-Gq (Box 18)
      (18-15)
    - Gore, Victor M. (Box 18)
      (18-16)
    - Gra-Gz (Box 18)
      (18-17)
    - Groesbeck, Alexander J. (Box 18)
      (18-18)
    - Haa-Ham (Box 18)
      (18-19)
    - Hall, Arthur (Box 18)
      (18-20)
    - Hamilton, Joan (Box 18)
      (18-21)
    - Han-Hh (Box 18)
      (18-22)
    - Hanchett, Benjamin (Box 18)
      (18-23)
    - Haynes, H.A. (Box 18)
      (18-24)
    - Hi-Hoo (Box 18)
      (18-25)
    - Hop-Hz (Box 18)
      (18-26)
    - Hubbard, Lucius (Box 18)
      (18-27)
    - I (Box 18)
      (18-28)
    - Institute for International Education (Box 18)
      (18-29)
    - International Committee of YMCA (Box 18)
      (18-30)
    - Ja-Jz (Box 18)
      (18-31)
    - Johnson, T.E. (Box 18)
      (18-32)
    - Ka-Ki (Box 18)
      (18-33)
    - Kahn, Albert (Box 18)
      (18-34)
    - Kelsey, Francis Willey (Box 18)
      (18-35)
    - Kj-Kz (Box 18)
      (18-36)
    - Kraus, E.H. (Box 18)
      (18-37)
    - Laa-Lh (Box 18)
      (18-38)
    - Li-Lz (Box 18)
      (18-39)
    - Lloyd, Walter (Box 18)
      (18-40)
    - Maa-Mb (Box 18)
      (18-41)
    - McA-Mh (Box 18)
      (18-42)
    - Mi-Mn (Box 18)
      (18-43)
    - Moa-Mz (Box 18)
      (18-44)
    - Murfin, James Orin (Box 18)
      (18-45)
    - Na-Nh (Box 18)
      (18-46)
    - Ni-Nz (Box 18)
      (18-47)
    - Oa-Oz (Box 18)
      (18-48)
    - Pa-Pe (Box 18)
      (18-49)
    - Pf-Pk (Box 18)
      (18-49a)
    - Pardon, E.C. (Box 18)
      (18-50)
    - Pitkin, William (Box 18)
      (18-51)
    - Pl-Q (Box 18)
      (18-52)
    - Ra-Rz (Box 18)
      (18-53)
    - Ramsay, William M. (Box 18)
      (18-54)
    - Regents (Box 18)
      (18-55)
    - Riggs, Frances (Box 19)
      (19-2)
    - Riggs, Henry E. (Box 19)
      (19-3)
    - Robbins, Frank (Box 19)
      (19-4)
    - Sa-Sm (Box 19)
      (19-5)
    - Sawyer, Walter (Box 19)
      (19-6)
    - Shepard, J.F. (Box 19)
      (19-7)
    - Smith, Shirley Wheeler (Box 19)
      (19-8)
    - Smith, Shirley Wheeler (Box 19)
      (19-9)
    - Sn-Sz (Box 19)
      (19-10)
    - Stone, Ralph (Box 19)
      (19-11)
    - Ta-Tz (Box 19)
      (19-12)
    - Treasurer's Reports (Box 19)
      (19-13)
    - U (Box 19)
      (19-14)
    - United States (Box 19)
      (19-15)
    - V (Box 19)
      (19-16)
    - Waa-Waz (Box 19)
      (19-17)
    - War Department (Box 19)
      (19-18)
    - Ward, Marcus L. (Box 19)
      (19-19)
    - Wea-Wh (Box 19)
      (19-20)
    - White, A.E. (Box 19)
      (19-21)
    - Whitney, A.S. (Box 19)
      (19-22)
    - Wia-Woz (Box 19)
      (19-23)
    - X,Y,Z (Box 19)
      (19-24)
- Miscellaneous President's Office Files, 1920-1924; 1 linear feet
  Miscellaneous President's Office Files (1 linear ft.) consists of topical files on University matters. Multiple files in this series concern the awarding of honorary degrees, the search for a dean of women in 1922, and general university administration.
  - Dean's meetings, 1920-1921 (Box 22)
    (22-1)
  - Honorary degrees conferred in
    - 1921, 1920-1921 (Box 22)
      (22-2)
    - 1922, 1921-1922 (Box 22)
      (22-3)
    - 1923, 1922-1923 (Box 22)
      (22-4)
    - 1924, 1917-1924 (Box 22)
      (22-5)
    - 1925, 1922-1925 (Box 22)
      (22-6)
  - Search for a Dean of Women, 1922; 2 folders (Box 22)
    (22-7; 22-8)
  - Helen Newberry Residence, 1924 (Box 22)
    (22-9)
  - Graff Fellowship, 1924 (Box 22)
    (22-11)
  - Meeting with the University physicians and surgeons at the Michigan Union, 1921 (Box 22)
    (22-12)
  - Conference of college presidents, 1922-1923 (Box 22)
    (22-13)
  - Commission of Inquiry on the University Hospital, 1922 (Box 22)
    (22-14)
  - Proposed building for the School of Music, 1920-1921 (Box 22)
    (22-15)
  - Newspaper clippings concerning western states speaking trip, 1921-1922 (Box 22)
    (22-17)
  - Outlines of the President's Reports, 1921-1922; 1922-1923 (Box 22)
    (22-20)
  - Outlines for president's report, 1923-1924 (Box 22)
    (22-20a)
  - Phillips Scholarships, 1920-1921 (Box 22)
    (22-21)
  - Francis E. Riggs Foundation, 1923-1924 (Box 22)
    (22-22)
  - Resolutions, letters of appreciation, etc., 1922-1923 (Box 22)
    (22-23)
  - Senate Council, 1921-1925 (Box 22)
    (22-24)
  - Calvin Coolidge and the Republican National Convention (pamphlets), 1924 (Box 22)
    (22-25)
  - Training of social workers in Michigan, 1921 (Box 22)
    (22-26)
  - Trip of W.J. Hussey to South Africa, 1924 (Box 22)
    (22-27)
  - Notes on faculty meetings, 1920-1922 (Box 22)
  - University of Michigan miscellanea (Box 22)
- Personal Materials
  Personal Materials (0.5 linear ft.) consists of letters of congratulations, memorial materials following Burton's death, and letters received following Burton's nominating speech for Calvin Coolidge in 1924.
  - Letters of congratulations upon Burton's appointment as President of the University of Michigan, 1920; 3 folders (Box 19)
    (19-25; 19-26; 19-27)
  - Letters concerning Burton's speech nominating Calvin Coolidge for the Presidency, June-July 1924; 2 folders (Box 19)
    (19-28; 19-29)
  - Letters of condolence on the death of Burton, 1925; 2 folders (Box 19)
    (19-31; 19-32)
  - Calvin Coolidge's memorial to Burton, 1925 (Box 19)
    (19-33)
  - Letters from Arthur Vandenberg to Mrs. Burton, 1928 (Box 19)
    (19-34)
  - Doctoral thesis from Yale University, entitled, "The Philosophical Basis of Augustine's Doctrine of Sin", 1907 (Box 19)
  - Guestbook used at inauguration of Burton as President of Smith College, 1910 (Box 19)
  - Biographical material, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Personal miscellanea, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Academic and other certificates (Folder 1)
    (located at Ac)
- Speeches and Articles
  The Speeches and Articles series includes manuscripts and drafts from throughout Burton's professional life, but primarily from 1909 to 1925 when he was a college president.
  - 1901, 1906 (Box 20)
    (20-1)
  - 1909 (Box 20)
    (20-2)
  - 1910 (Box 20)
    (20-3)
  - 1911 (Box 20)
    (20-4)
  - 1912 (Box 20)
    (20-5)
  - 1913 (Box 20)
    (20-6)
  - 1914 (Box 20)
    (20-7)
  - 1915 (Box 20)
    (20-8)
  - 1916 (Box 20)
    (20-9)
  - 1917 (Box 20)
    (20-10)
  - 1918 (Box 20)
    (20-11)
  - 1919 (Box 20)
    (20-12)
  - 1920 (Box 20)
    (20-13)
  - 1921 (Box 20)
    (20-14)
  - 1922 (Box 20)
    (20-15)
  - 1923 (Box 20)
    (20-16)
  - 1923 (Box 20)
    (20-17)
  - 1924 (Box 20)
    (20-18)
  - Speech nominating Calvin Coolidge for the Presidency, June 1924 (Box 20)
    (20-18a)
  - Undated, 1920-1925 (Box 20)
    (20-19)
  - Undated (Box 20)
    (20-20)
- Scrapbooks/Newspaper clippings
  The Scrapbooks/Newspaper clippings series dates from 1895 to 1925. Although mainly consisting of newspaper articles, the scrapbooks also contain programs, memorabilia, and personal photographs.
  - (Early life, Carleton College), 1895-1907 (Box 21)
  - (Yale University), 1903-1907 (Box 21)
    (includes programs and other memorabilia)
  - (Yale University, Smith College), 1908-1909 (Box 21)
  - (University of Minnesota), 1917-1920 (Box 21)
    (compiled by Josephine M. Fredericks)
  - (University of Michigan affairs), 1920-1921 (Box 21)
  - (University of Michigan affairs), 1922-1923 (Box 21)
  - (Burton's speech nominating Calvin Coolidge for the Presidency), 1924 (Box 21)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 21)
- University of Minnesota Topical Files
  The University of Minnesota Topical Files series is a miscellanea of subject and organizational files from the period when Burton was president of the University of Minnesota. The files are not specific to university affairs, but rather deal with Burton's and the university's involvement in different organizations. The files also reflect Burton's religious background and his work with church-based organizations.
  - International Committee of the YMCA, 1918-1920 (Box 23)
  - Military training camp, 1919-1920 (Box 23)
  - Commission on Education of the International Congregational Council, 1917-1920 (Box 23)
    (22-18)
  - Congregational Education Society, 1918 (Box 23)
- Photographs
  see also outsize folder Ac
  The Photographs series includes both portraits and family photos. There are also photos of the wedding of his daughter in the William L. Clements Library, views of the President's House, and photos of Burton's funeral procession along South University Ave.
  - Family, early photos, and friends (Box 23)
  - Family, later photos (Box 23)
  - Foreign students' party (Box 23)
  - Portraits (Box 23)
  - Funeral of Marion Le Roy Burton (Box 23)
    includes South University Avenue scene
  - Wedding of daughter Theodosia in Clements Library; views of President's House (Box 23)
  - Commencement and miscellaneous (Box 23)
Selective Index to Correspondence
Adams, Henry Carter, 1851-1921.
1921 [1-1]; 1922 [5-1]
American Association for International Cooperation.
1922 [9-9]; 1923 [10-21]
American Birth Control League.
1923 [9-9]
American Council on Education.
1921 [1-3]; 1921-1922 [5-3]; 1922-1923 [9-10]; 1923-1924 [13-8]; 1924-1925 [17-15]